When you argue with your girlfriend
Didn't I already teach you once?
Why don't you ever question whether
Maybe it's because you didn't explain it well
So this is about the interaction between people
and the current interaction between humans and machines
imbalance point
because we feel that
Interacting with machines
The machine must be dumber than me
So I need to teach it many times
That's perfectly normal
But when AGI arrives
It should be as intelligent as I am
You should learn it after I teach you once
People's expectations change over time
The day your grandma
scolds the robot at home saying
I already taught you once, why don't you get it yet?
that's when you'll know AGI has arrived
Our world's AGI is judged by this
Our measuring standard grows from Grandma
Grows from this kind of grandma
It's her expectation
If I've already told you once
Don't make this mistake again
Hi hello everyone, welcome back to Sidechat
I'm Mia, editor at INSIDE
I'm Fox
Today, we're thrilled to have as our guest on this episode of SAI Q&A
Dr. Hui-Hsin Chi, Vice President of Research at Google DeepMind
Dr. Chi, please say hello to everyone
Hello everyone
Dr., could you please briefly introduce your background to everyone
and the position you primarily hold at Google DeepMind
as well as your main research focus areas
I was born and raised in Taiwan
I was born in Tamsui
Then at around 15 years old
I went to study in the United States with my parents
Because my mother went to pursue her PhD at that time
So I attended high school there
After finishing that high school, I went to university there
And completed my master's and PhD there as well
After finishing my studies, I went to work in California
Working at a research center
A place called Xerox PARC (Palo Alto Research Center)
Interrupting this
I think Xerox PARC (Palo Alto Research Center) was a very significant place for me.
I looked into your background
You actually worked there!
That was back in 1997-98
Yes
Because I must mention this matter
In 1998, Apple sued Microsoft
And asked why their Windows..
Copied the look of Mac's operating system
Then Bill Gates said
No actually, we all went to Xerox PARC to see it
So we're all the same
So that was the time when that incident happened
Yes
When I first went to Xerox PARC
That could be considered its second renaissance
So at that time, doing research there
you could say it was a top-tier place
Yes, everyone can imagine
in the past with Microsoft's Windows operating system
Or what we now see in Mac
the operating system
whether it's the mouse, user interface, etc.
were all originally developed by Xerox PARC
At that time, what the research center invented
Yes, and the reason it was established in California at that time
was precisely to be as far away from headquarters as possible
Xerox was a photocopier company
He was originally on the East Coast
His main headquarters is on the East Coast
Then established a research division
Completely independent from the parent company
It's located right next to Stanford University
So it's a very, very special place
Quite legendary, and they say
That in the past, Jobs and Bill Gates each went in to take a look
Then we learned from others' work
Then we copied it and went global
Then claimed we learned everything there
So that was the prevailing atmosphere at the time
Is that a great place in terms of a research field?
A top-tier place, and it was also where we were at the time
For example, Ethernet originated there as the birthplace of networking
And the laser printer was also invented there
graphical user interface
laser printing
even the audio-visual technologies we commonly use today
video conferencing
It was all invented at Xerox PARC
Things from the 1980s
Why at that particular time - though you're from the 90s and 80s
But I'm curious why that place had..
Is it able to do so? Is it collaborating with the military or not at all?
What's interesting about your question is that...
Why did Silicon Valley later produce so much innovation?
In fact, its connection to Silicon Valley's entire origins..
Why do we call it Silicon Valley
Of course it's related to semiconductors
But before semiconductors
What's another interesting aspect about semiconductors
during World War II
what was the most important research being conducted
it was about radio
such as detection-related research
So Stanford University at that time in the 1940s
was especially doing cutting-edge work in radio sensing
and was a top-tier institution
That's why Stanford's engineering program was already very strong back then
So this Xerox PARC in the 1970s
When establishing research centers
Because Stanford has a Triangle Research Park
Everyone wanted to set up research centers there
So that's the reason
It has been there for forty or fifty years
Yes, because he was probably originally doing this kind of
high-end, technological, cutting-edge stuff
Recently, many research talents have gathered there
And what's really interesting is that every day when I drive to work
I pass by a very inconspicuous
place that looks like a sheet metal shack
just a flat, single-layer place
That place is actually the birthplace where semiconductors were originally invented
And there's an itropy plack there
Just an indicator cup telling you
This is the birthplace of semiconductors
So no matter how Taiwan's semiconductor leadership stands now
We still have to go back to look at the origins
That's right, exactly
So when I saw what Xerox was doing
I really thought it was amazing
So you stayed until around 2010
Yes, I was at Xerox PARC for about 13 years
Then I realized that just doing research wasn't enough
We also needed to work on practical applications
That's why I ended up going to Google
What kind of work did you do initially?
I was originally working primarily on
visual graphics research
Then as I worked, I discovered the web was quite interesting
So I started doing a lot of analytical work related to the web
Some big data work
At that time, we didn't even call it big data yet
It was just called data mining or data engineering
That was around the early 2000s
Then we continued until around 2007-2008
In fact, the first thing my team invented was
Twitter's first recommendation engine
So we started moving in the direction of web analytics
From the field of big data moving towards social media
So we later did a lot of social computing
And social media research
Because of this, I ended up going to Google
Because I just mentioned Xerox
Because they conduct a lot of academic research
They've done extensive research
But in reality, we don't seem to have any real impression of it
Xerox truly developed all these technologies
and created an entirely new business model
or perhaps Xerox should have disappeared by now
more or less
So I'm curious about
why he's at the top level here
but hasn't actually created a consumer-grade
and phenomenally successful product
So academic research must ultimately find ways
to be applied in ways that impact all of humanity's lives
Exactly
Just like us researchers and R&D personnel in this field
People often don't understand that technology is just one aspect of it
If you really want to make money
You need to be able to develop a business model
And this model could be, for example, an advertising model
or a subscription-based model
or many other ways to make money
your technology isn't connected to a business model
you won't be able to start a business
But it's also because of companies like Google
They invented—though it started simply as
interconnected understanding, ranking algorithms
Then they added ads, and it took off like a rocket
Yes
Up until now
So regarding the matter of adding advertisements
In fact, what many people might not understand is that
It's about accelerating commerce
He is actually an acceleration
So he has value
His value starts from this acceleration
So from that point in time
That has already begun
For example, we all talk about machine learning
and things like machine learning
Start doing what was just recommended
It must be related to ranking and machine learning
It must be super positively correlated
So at that time
I've already started thinking about AI
Back then, when we heard about AI, we thought
This isn't like the kind I imagined that could talk
And converse with you fluently
You say it's very different from what's in sci-fi works
I mean, it's used in advertising again
And it's working on this algorithm
You seem..
doing very detailed things
it feels so superficial
a bit superficial
no, I mean superficial
It's really great and profitable
But this algorithm is also amazing
Machine learning is fantastic too
But it doesn't seem to be changing the world, does it?
something you think is amazing
The reason for this is actually because
many people
including our listeners and such
Over the past two to three decades
with the emergence of Google
it has become a ubiquitous method
since we all have screens
If there's a screen, it must be
Reading things must be sequential
If it's sequential, there must be permutations and combinations
And this part about permutations and combinations
Why did the algorithm later
over these ten, twenty years
keep becoming more precise
keep pushing forward
Research is being conducted in this area
The reason actually is that
This entire advertisement as well
Or the search results we see like this
ranking is good
its accuracy only needs to improve by 0.1%
do you know how significant that improvement is
it makes a lot of money
A lot of money
You're like Google's search ranking
That part
That side of the business
Approximately only 200 billion USD
Right?
For the entire market
The total combined could easily exceed 500 billion
Then you just need to improve by 0.1%
1% would be 5 billion dollars
Even 0.1% would still be 500 million dollars
These are all enormous numbers
So 0.1 makes such a big difference
Because on one hand it's advertising
Just improving by 0.1% or 1%
Can earn a lot of money
Another aspect is if we can use these algorithms
to reduce its cost
or improve, for example, the data center's
certain energy consumption or efficiency metrics
Improve by 1% 5%
It costs less
Saves a lot of money
Which means better
This also extends to the point that
Nowadays, people often talk about
The cost of Google searches
Each query has a low cost
has been compressed to extremely low costs
But now with AI
when generating responses to queries
the cost may be just a fraction of the original
10x or 20x improvements
It feels like
a clash between different eras' logics, right?
Exactly, so it's optimization in this regard
How can we reduce costs
These issues are still in the research phase
Because we need to figure out
When to use more advanced algorithms
When to use more brute-force algorithms
These are all research directions
OK
I think before a certain point in time
It's Google's product line
To put it this way, it's a bit messy
For example, after Gemini
Back in 2021, 2022
Then last year with Bard, suddenly everything was renamed
I said at that time
Renamed again
I renamed it again at that time
Changed to one called Gemini
But to be honest
After Gemini
You finally feel everything is in order
Then 1.5 2.0 2.5 Pro
It progressed step by step like this
But during this process, I could sense that
Did it go through many phases in between?
I feel like there's something going on
from its different names
it feels like there are tons of projects running simultaneously
the feeling is like there's something happening
Google brand
And then I also have DeepMind
When do you think this was
Starting to gradually converge
And up until now
This relatively better situation
I think this matter actually
May also have some connection with the company culture
Indeed
Google, being a software company
So software companies tend
To be more like that
a diverse approach to management where multiple methods flourish together
because it might think that
software is the kind of thing
that can suddenly emerge and take off
A new idea
It might have come from the person on the left side
Or it could be from the person on the right side
Or maybe from someone behind you
It could also be the person before you doing it
So when working at Google
You often get this feeling
It's like when I'm working on this thing
But there are also five teams
Five other groups are working on this
So software companies' organizational structure
Tends to favor this bottom-up approach
Hardware companies tend to be more top-down
One of the reasons for this is that
hardware is essentially
a concept of integration
You want everything to fit perfectly
So it will be more top-down
Not to mention hardware companies like Apple
Where the phone case and its screen..
How to integrate them together
It's all extremely precise
So this kind of company's culture
Will be more top-down
Because it has the capacity to spare
It can simultaneously develop various projects
And the question you asked
What makes it particularly good is one reason
Because software is currently undergoing a major transformation
Because the previous approach to software
typically involved developing many different modules
and completing them all
and then integrate it
integrate them together
but now with the emergence of large models
many things are done using the converge method
It's a module that handles many different tasks
So this direction of software development
Is becoming more like a top-down organization
Speaking of this point
I have to say because of this
that is Sergey Brin
the co-founder
greatly
He did make a comeback, didn't he?
At some point, it seemed like he really got serious and came back
Do you think his comeback also helped make things more unified?
Yes, definitely
Moreover, his personality is very proactive
He's the type of person who really enjoys getting things done
He's a very execution-focused type of founder
Because I saw in the interview he was just wearing shorts
then at Google
very relaxed
very chill
super chill
But he's actually very proactive in what he does
He may appear very chill on the surface
But in reality he's extremely proactive
Because I saw in his interview that
He probably stepped down around 2019 or 2020
Meaning he stopped being CEO
Then it was somewhat like being forced into retirement
Then one day he happened to meet someone from OpenAI who said
Why are you in this retired state? Now is the time to fight the most.
You should come back.
He seemed to have been provoked later.
And then he came back—now we have to return to working in the office
Yes, and in fact he has always been the President of Technology
during his time at Google
As for the CEO, that was Larry Page
As for Sergey, he has always been more focused on..
the direction of technology R&D
but to some extent you could think of it this way
that is to say, Google went through a period
in fact, you could call it peacetime
Yes
15 years later
As we just discussed, this topic is a great example
He might think that this 0.1% improvement
500 million dollars
For him, it's not exciting
Although for us developers, we might think
that's interesting
If this idea could be realized, there would be a
for example, a 0.5% or even 1% improvement
so at Google Research
we were constantly looking for those 5% or 10% improvements
or even higher levels of disruption
We actually managed to find it in the end
And the disruption turned out to be even greater than we imagined
Especially since the transformer concept was originally
proposed by researchers at Google at that time
The result is a flourishing of diverse ideas
Ultimately, the credit still goes back to Google
Yes, and you could say that
Such an important discovery is actually very difficult to..
Tied up inside a box
This thing will naturally
Because its power is too great
Its capability is too remarkable
So this thing is really about
I personally believe it's truly changing the world
How could you possibly
let it go
No way
It really started after the .com boom in 2000
I think even he himself said this should be
Considered the greatest leap in human development
I originally thought that maybe
the development of mobile phones
smartphones has already advanced tremendously
so I originally thought that
to keep up with the internet
or the development of smartphones
any new invention during my lifetime
might not necessarily be something I'll get to see
Really? And then these large models emerged
I think it's quite possible
And the more I look at it, the more likely it seems
Right now it feels highly probable
Yes, about two or three years ago, people might have still been saying...
Just when ChatGPT first came out
It felt like there was a real, sudden pause in the conversation
And at that time, we were transitioning from Lambda to Bard
this journey
and finally evolved into the Gemini journey
is also because
there are many different people within Google
I feel that when we were working on Lambda
and Lambda's predecessor was a project called Mina
when we were working on Mina and Lambda
many people thought that
This feels like a toy
Same as GPT2
At that time, I think many people looked at GPT2
It seemed like it could do something
It's like you can't really do anything
That doesn't seem to work either
Yes
So do you really think that later
It's amazing compared to when it was still like a toy
What are the main differences in using it
I think the feeling at that time
There's a bit of similarity to a book in the business field
It's particularly interesting when discussing this
The Innovator's Dilemma
It's highly relevant
The feeling when using Lambda was that
it's fun to chat with it
But does this actually have any real use?
And its accuracy might not be that high
Sometimes it says some really strange things
Plus there's the hallucination problem
People might think these hallucination issues
might not be fixable
can't be fixed
then let's wait and see
So I think in fact
we started from sequence
this sequence transduction
in 2015, before Transformer
Another paper I consider even more important
That paper on sequence to sequence learning
At the time, we really should have realized
This was a transformative technology
but I think many people missed it
missed it in 2015
the Transformer paper came out in 2017
and missed it again
By 2019 or 2020
When we were discussing whether to launch this Lambda
Everyone missed it too
We had to wait until OpenAI released ChatGPT
And the main people inside ChatGPT
Several of them were from my former team
So you can see that
Some people on the team think
this is transformer technology
while others still consider it just a toy
The Innovator's Dilemma means that
often a new technology
may initially appear to be just an imitation
or even a counterfeit product
very cheap
yeah exactly
It doesn't feel like Google search, right
but we still put it up there
We're Google, you know
Yeah, so it's like
Just like we were talking about Xerox earlier
At that time, Xerox had laser printing
Then later came inkjet
When inkjet first came out, Xerox thought
This thing is too terrible
The print quality was very poor
low resolution
One of these is actually quite interesting to talk about
because of laser printing
it uses toner particles
Use this heat laser
Attach it to this paper
Inject it as a liquid
Spray it by injecting
Inkjet printer
We call it an inkjet printer
It sprays the ink onto the paper
"Spraying ink" sounds kinda lame
Is that what it means?
So the effect of spraying it in
Its resolution in fact
Was much lower than laser printing at that time
So the printed results were extremely poor
So the people at Xerox thought
This is an inferior technology
Why should we invest in this thing
So when we were working on Mina lambda
many people shared the same feeling
they thought this thing
could never be replaced
existing technology
So this is the Innovator's Dilemma
Yes, because actually
Given today's atmosphere at that time
I also think Google is really in a dilemma
Because it's like saying
Now I'm having hallucinations
And after the hallucinations are output
I must say even with today's AI
there's still an overview
there actually still is
but now people don't see it as a problem
It's now at an acceptable level
because everyone knows
that all AIs include everything, meaning
OpenAI, Claude, or any other company
Everyone has hallucinations
So now Google having hallucinations seems
not particularly serious
People would think
It's only been three years
People no longer see this as a serious issue
Quite remarkable
Yes, and I think this shows how quickly technology acceptance evolves
Or even users' evolution and expectations of them
will keep changing
Take our mobile phones for example
Back in the day when we saw those big brick phones
There's a mobile phone in the car
What happened then?
Wow, amazing! So impressive!
And what was it called before?
What is BB call called in Taiwan?
1997 BB call
Now who among us has a mobile phone
It has become completely commonplace
It's a very common thing, even with smartphones
You'd only find it strange if you didn't have one
So now we're at the point where
These have already become integrated into our daily lives
So you start to take it for granted
So I think this kind of AI technology
Is currently going through this same kind of transition
Because Google I/O was just one or two weeks ago
What do you think is inside?
Although that event was truly
I think it's
Personally, I believe it's been the past decade
Google's best Google I/O
Although many people disagree
But that's how I feel
I'm the only one in this editorial department who uses Android
And every time it's always during Apple's keynote
And everyone gets super excited waiting for it
But when it's Google's turn, nobody pays attention to me
Thank you for being our Google fan
I told you this feature is awesome
But then no one was listening to me
Oh, really?
But it's also because there was just too much content this time
Is there one that you personally feel
whether it's the company or you personally
you feel is your favorite
I would say now, last year 2024
When we announced at I/O
I said "Oh my God"
Now this multi-modality capability
The so-called multi-modality refers to this large model
Have you noticed multimodal
Have you noticed we used to often talk about
large language models, which are LLMs, right
text
Text language
But now we often refer to them as large models
The reason is because of their modality - different modalities
Such as image, video
or voice
audio
it's all integrated into this model
so in 2024, I think it's safe to say
It marks the beginning of multimodal large models
But at this year's 2025 I/O, I personally believe that
people will truly realize for the first time
what multimodal actually means
It's very similar to, for example, the Project Astra that I'm responsible for
this capability
it's this entire model, this large model
that can now coexist with you in the same environment
And because of the changes in that environment
it will make some appropriate responses
I would say that
even two or three years ago
I think this is incredible
It's unbelievable
This artificial intelligence
It can understand where I am right now when it's raining
Then if I ask where should I go to eat
It would suggest that if you don't want to get wet in the rain
You could walk to Taipei 101 or something like that
It just feels alive
you feel the future
the future is approaching
this matter of the future
I think there's another way to explain this
That is to say
Language large language models were previously somewhat described as
Because it is merely a language model
So when you communicate with it
It must communicate through language
This means it is confined to
a virtual world
You must go through this language interface
you can connect with it
but now these large models
are actually capable of understanding
or even just
Realize what kind of environment you're in
This indicates it has already integrated into a
human living environment
So this capability
This is already moving forward
So what everyone will see in 2025
I think is exactly this thing
If everyone could watch the video
Last year
Astra's video was filmed in the office
showing you what the office looks like
including things like what was written on the blackboard
This year they released an even more amazing video
It's about a teenager
who's fixing a bicycle
with relevant situational context
very complete
Does it still look like it's in Beta now?
Or is it in some other state?
You could say it's still in Beta
OK, I have a cell phone right in my pocket
But what I mean is
Will we really have the chance to see
and use it?
For example, is this a visible future?
Can we show them this?
Sure
I just brought a prototype
You can't use it
But we can show it to you
The prototype you presented at Google I/O
Is actually our prototype
And it's running Astra on it
So the software inside is Astra
OK, I'll take a look
This is the only device in Taiwan running Astra
Yes, this should be my first time here
Can I take a look?
But wearing it like this just makes it regular glasses
It actually looks really good on you
I think it's really cool
Thank you
That's great
And it's very light, right?
Because
You can feel it
Because I've used it
So this is already
Because I have Meta
This is lighter than Meta
Wow
But is the key reason it's lighter because of the battery?
The battery, the processor inside, and all those components are closely related
Because originally when I mentioned Astra, what we saw was
Because it's a smartphone
Because of this carrier device, I think it might
He was using it on his phone in the video
while fixing a bicycle
so we're not sure if this is the final form factor
but since everyone's been starting to recently
We've been doing this for over a decade
this Google Glass
I remember it vividly back in 2012
when a friend of mine came back from Google I/O
I still have one pair
The one from 2012
Then I put them on and came to the office
This looks a lot like a Saiyan
That's the Saiyan from Dragon Ball
The scouter for measuring power levels
You can look all you want
But you won't feel that feeling
And I also have another memory from that time
There was a reporter in San Francisco at that time
He was wearing that pair of glasses when he got beaten
I remember that news story vividly too
Then recently he said we're wearing these things now
and no one on the street thinks
they'll get punched
no one finds it too strange
No one would feel that their privacy has been violated
or anything like that
That might also be related to this situation
And people are now accustomed to filming with their smartphones everywhere
It's also somewhat related
I think when smartphones first appeared
everyone had one in their hands, able to record videos
and take photos
At that time, many people would still think
Wow, you're filming everywhere
Wouldn't that violate my privacy?
Now nobody even thinks about that anymore
Some people might think
they just want it to tell them and be done with it
but in over 95% of cases, that's really all there is to it
that's just how it is
I think, actually, let me share a little anecdote
What I find really interesting is
when I came back to Taiwan and watched the local news
I kept wondering why every time there's a car accident
Someone already recorded it
How is this so amazing
Everyone has one - truly everyone has a phone
You get videos instantly
But Taiwan is very accustomed to this
We have dashcams in our cars
We actually have CCTV cameras on every road
Even motorcycles have one - riders wear dashcams on their helmets
Similar things are already out there
And many people do it to protect their rights
So these videos are indeed everywhere
So having glasses now isn't actually too strange
I think the most interesting part
Going back to what we were discussing earlier
is that because these glasses
have a camera built into them
This camera enables artificial intelligence
to simultaneously
within your environment
perceive your situation
It's raining. It's not raining.
What sign are you looking at?
For example, even when you go shopping in the future
You take it with you and you think that
This dress looks very nice
It might even remember to say that in the future
You think clothes with this style look very nice
I have another usage scenario
I think perhaps friends who are into fashion
might find it very interesting
For example, when we use
Maybe in the future we'll use Project Astra
this kind of capability
you go into your closet and rummage through your clothes
it learns your style
then when you go shopping
It says you already have three navy shirts
Maybe you should consider another color
The other day on Twitter
A bunch of people were discussing AI ideas
This is one of them
They said, "I'll just take a picture of what's in my closet right now."
all the clothes
Help me choose what's right for me
Order it directly from somewhere
Or perhaps they love books
Book lovers might just glance at the bookshelf
And say these are the books I own
Then it says, "Can you suggest what I should read next?"
Yes
So when I saw the glasses appear at that time
Because Meta's doesn't have a display
But I believe soon, everyone will catch up with this
It's about the display thing
Going back to my initial idea
I can detect
Then I can have a passerby come over
I can tell his fortune for him
I'm just talking nonsense - it's the first terrible application that came to my mind
There are many similar cases because it can detect
You would naturally use some strange methods
It starts just like making an app
People will create all kinds of apps on it
Then another new renaissance of apps will begin
This is what excites me most about this matter
That's exactly why I mentioned earlier
I saw this thing and it's amazing
And I also know it should be capable of doing it
But it's probably something that will happen within the next year or two
I think the part you mentioned
can be interpreted in another way
that is, once this kind of capability emerges
if you are... we often feel nowadays that
Whether it's mobile devices or anything else
You would truly feel like moving forward
Should mobile devices still be presented to people
in that same old way?
It's like the issue with apps
The matter of having to download an app
And then you have to
For example, you could put it this way
I often have to help my mom with things on her phone
Then I tell her she needs to download this app first
And then enter her password
A whole bunch of troublesome issues, right?
These things should disappear in the future
Exactly - AI will handle it for you
You won't need to worry about those things at all
AI will take care of it automatically when needed
You can imagine, for example
If he's wearing glasses
And then he notices the laundry detergent is running out
He looks at the detergent and says
Can you order something for me from PX Mart?
Indeed
What else do you need to find?
Find it through an app
And then click there?
This kind of operation will probably become standard in the future
But what if I want to play Pokémon on it?
Actually, I think you've raised a very good question - why do I say that?
Because there's a lot of technology involved
It probably all started with games
Things like VR and XR
Augmented reality and VR technologies
Many of them also began with games initially
That part has actually been in development for a long time
I think it's quite mature
And the entire mechanism is already in place
So I really think this is
The talent is already here
And you see if
This is inevitable
He'll say at that time: I can catch Pokémon up there
I believe
there will definitely be
and then suddenly there'll be a limited-edition Pokémon glasses
this killer app
I think your audience
might already be thinking
about starting a new company to do this
that's for sure
Because just watching that video made me feel
There are too many possibilities
You can add many layers on top
Exactly what you just mentioned
I shop in various contexts
But people always need some new MR stuff
to be applied on top
and then
Imagination will be better
I think what you're asking
is a very good question
and the reason it ties in well with the topic is
Most people, when they see this kind of new..
in the era of technology
Sometimes their imagination
In fact, it's very limited
Really
Then he would think
Can you help me with this AI
to build better apps
or create better
using old ideas
Thinking with old ideas
But we need to break out of that box
The most important thing is
The box I'm currently thinking in
Is it correct inside the box?
Perhaps it's completely outside the box
So if anyone is interested
You really should take a look
These videos related to Astral
Let's take a look
When it comes to multimodal capabilities
There are actually many things that can be achieved
I think actually
when we talk about
the recent collaboration between OpenAI and Jony Ive
he actually also said that
We need to create a new device
Meaning it shouldn't just be a phone
It should have a
Because currently there are rumors saying
There's a rumor about a pendant now
With a camera at the front
And apparently it's the same concept
Meaning it has a camera
It already understands you
your surrounding world
so it makes judgments
though I think that diagram is really ugly
It's just a rumor
So this is what I think
Will be one of the most interesting things next
So since you think this is so interesting
and also will collaborate with
What about Taiwan?
Taiwan in this aspect
because it's software
In the past, we were
Although we excel in semiconductors
Our relationship with AI is
The peninsula - a nation of crystal manufacturing
Then I looked back at your past interviews
Because we have many robots
So what about these opportunities in the physical world
Or in hardware?
I believe there's definitely a hardware aspect to this
Of course, the entire world's
supply chain for these 3C products is undergoing changes
So this aspect is certainly [a factor]
There will also be some impact on Taiwan
But looking at the overall industry development
I also think that Taiwan's semiconductor sector
Especially in the manufacturing aspect
Its position should be quite difficult to shake
The part I find more interesting is probably
because of these hardware changes
there will be many new opportunities
Can this company in Taiwan be able to
Seize this opportunity
to develop new hardware capabilities
or new applications
or even because of these reasons
sparking trends in certain software
trends
the integration of hardware and software
I see other numbers
NVIDIA said they have an insection program
They were originally based in Taiwan, probably around two or three years ago
There might have only been single-digit numbers
It is said that in the past two years
the entire big bang has transformed into what
there are a thousand or so
of these AI-related startups in Taiwan
But in terms of hardware-software integration, we may not have seen it yet
But clearly this is a huge opportunity
And if Taiwan can do well in integrating hardware and software
Leveraging the capabilities of large language models
It's indeed a huge opportunity
Like what we were just discussing
Perhaps future new games in smart glasses
What's the reasoning behind this
Companies in Taiwan can't do it
This is definitely something that can be achieved
I've noticed recently
But that requires a new way of thinking
Indeed, you know Taiwan had some
really popular hardware products before
kind of like on Kickstarter in the US
many of them actually developed hardware
Then there might be a recording card installed above
so it can transform into
and inside it might be using Gemini
or other companies' large language models
And then it just clicked
Then we started taking meeting minutes
Things like that throughout the year
Later we realized it was a Chinese company
But I see it can generate
revenue of over 100 million NTD in a year
just from this single
kind of idea
So I think this kind of opportunity is tremendously significant
Personally, I don't know about you, but for me...
I recently developed an app
It's kind of a silly app
It is used for OCR business cards
Then inside it
is powered by this Gemini Pro
It is used to recognize business cards
Then the categories inside
It's a very simple and small application
But I can feel that this thing's
capability is very good
And it might not even need the best model
to accomplish this task
Of course, if it integrates with hardware
I think it presents a fantastic opportunity
What are your thoughts on robots, for example?
How do you view this matter of robots?
As for robots, this aspect is about...
As we just mentioned..
Because previously using large language models
could only connect with this kind of virtual world
our online world
could connect with the online virtual world
We need robots because
humans still live in a physical world
a physical world
so if you want this artificial intelligence
can exist in the physical world
if there is an interface
then you definitely need robots
the approach before robots
the current approach with large models
the previous approach was very traditional
as we who studied computer science all know
meaning everything was kept separate
The visual module is the visual module
The audio module is the audio module
The arm module is the arm module
The planning module is the module for thinking
It's another module
And then integrate them together
The approach is different now
Because all these capabilities
Putting everything into a single model
This is somewhat similar to our human brain
When walking, it's not like
You're not consciously thinking "I should move my hand this way"
I need to move my leg like this
so I can move forward, right?
It should be able to do it in one smooth motion, right?
So I think in the next five years, robots..
There will likely be a significant transformation
due to the opportunity presented by multimodal large models
which is already revolutionizing this field
Let me elaborate further
We traditionally think of this robot as
a single arm being a robot
Perhaps what Elon Musk is advocating now is humanoid
while Mr. Jensen Huang is talking about a complete one
Then comes the humanoid type
They come in various sizes and different forms
Nothing particularly special, or perhaps each type actually...
Which one will be the next generation?
One particularly fascinating aspect right now
Regarding the question you asked
What makes it so interesting is
The single-arm robots of the past
It can typically perform tasks within a factory setting
Using one hand to carry out repetitive actions
Now, with the opportunity presented by large models
It can be made to work with both hands simultaneously
So now there are two hands that can
Think about it
Yes, you—I don't know if you've ever experienced that kind of pain
Like maybe your hand got injured or something
Then suddenly one day you need to brush
Just the act of brushing teeth
You have to twist open that
Requires both hands, right?
There are many, many things you'll discover
that actually require both hands
But when using both hands
there's actually a coordination issue involved
Back then
This arm here was controlled by one module
While that arm over there was controlled by another module
And you needed them to coordinate with each other
Do you know how difficult this research was back then?
How difficult was it?
Now there are no problems at all
Now it's advanced to what extent
The videos we produce demonstrate that
we can directly instruct it by saying
I want you to fold this paper exactly like this
and it can accomplish all of these tasks
Hold the paper like this
Then fold it like this
It can do origami
Wow, it can fold straight
The dexterity of its hands
The manual dexterity has now reached a level where it can perform
It has already surpassed you - it can make origami
While you can't even assemble a single model
So sometimes when I watch this video before
They say this plumber won't have any problems within five years by visual estimation
I'm not that optimistic
Fixing cars would be fine though
Because people are saying white-collar jobs will be replaced immediately
While blue-collar jobs can still hold on
It feels like because at that time there was debate saying
You don't have enough data to train the robots
And collecting this data is very difficult
Then recently when I was looking at NVIDIA
I suspect Google might have something similar
Which is they've already started making robots dream directly
Start operating these things
Is Google doing something similar?
In a virtual environment
We're not just in a virtual environment
You have the opportunity to go find some
We recently have Gemini Robotics
Capabilities just released in March
Now it can achieve some truly amazing things
For example, it has never seen a basketball before
You tell it to "dunk the basketball in the hoop"
It can still understand this command
And then perform this action
It has already achieved a higher-level behavior
What I mean is
Because in the past, if you wanted to train me to perform a dunk move
I would probably have to demonstrate the dunk myself first for it to see
Then it learned about this thing
But now the training method has become
I give it 10,000 times, show it 10,000 basketball videos
After it understands that
It understands that dunking means this
This was how it was a few years ago
Now it's different
Because I see that they now
that NVIDIA is saying
they currently have a world physics engine
and it's somewhat like playing a game
Train it extensively
so we don't have to constantly work on instances
to create videos or perform actual tasks
because it has already seen many other videos
It understands these concepts
what kind of state it is
The most interesting part is
From your understanding
People are actually starting to implement these things
Is this called real production now?
In this entire production world
This is what's happening right now
We're currently figuring out how to approach this matter
Because so far on the robot side
most are handling these highly repetitive tasks
on industrial production lines
The industrial type
Yes, some repetitive tasks on a production line
And potentially hazardous ones
Or those requiring high precision
requires very high-level work
As we move forward, you can see
why we're talking about humanoid robots and such
The reason is that
We'd prefer to move forward with some
affordable robots that can handle household chores
like folding laundry
or doing the laundry
Cooking
These issues, washing hair
Especially I think
Taiwan's long-term care issues
in 5 years or 10 years
will there really be
more affordable robots
that can help with household chores
I think humans are incredibly contradictory when talking about this matter
What contradiction?
The reason for the contradiction is
First, on one hand we're very afraid
Replaced
AI or robots have taken over our
white-collar jobs or blue-collar jobs
Yet on the other hand we realize
We're actually facing a severe labor shortage
We're critically short on caregiving staff
Because I recently saw news reports saying
Nearly all hospitals across Taiwan essentially have no available beds
Because of this nurse
The shortage of nurses
Then causing the core issue of this entire matter
Will likely emerge on a large scale within a few years
What's your take on this matter?
So now there's quite a lot of interest in medical robots
among developers
That's precisely the reason
There are some very simple tasks
such as delivering medicine
or even things like
turning over patients
Is this kind of problem correct?
Every single thing you do now
in the hospital requires nurses to handle
Is it possible that
There's a turning-over robot
Scheduled to turn everyone over at set times
That makes sense
And because its hands are now very dexterous
So it might be possible
And the entire scanning process is very concrete
Your vision makes the judgment
Because I feel that in the past
People would want to do this thing
which is healthcare
There must be some physical object to assist
and then every incident would
there should be a machine to do this
for example, turning over should be done by a bed
it can help you sit up a bit
and then lie back down
Then you'll need to buy this bed
And if
I need to take him to the bathroom
I'll need a machine to transport him there
But if it's a humanoid robot
combined with its multimodal capabilities
it should be able to master all these skills
There are many technical details involved here
Like what we were talking about earlier regarding dining
this food delivery robot
how well they perform
how they integrate into different restaurants
Different restaurants have their own sizes
There may be issues with all of them
Different hospitals will also have
Application problems in this regard
So in this regard,
there's an urgent need to resolve
then you can imagine that
there exists a multimodal large model
If it can be used to perform such tasks
In the past, you might have had to go to different hospitals
with different beds
and different specifications
Different sizes of hospital beds
Location of the ward
Everything is problematic
Right?
In the future, we imagine that..
Just put it in and let it scan through
Yes, showing you the map - got it?
Okay
Starting medication delivery
Because you can think of it this way
If I were the head of a hospital
And I hired a nurse
Then I told them that
I need someone to help deliver the medicine
The patient is over here
The medical order is here
The medicine is over here
Please do this thing
He should be able to do it right away, right?
This is so sci-fi, oh my god
Medical robots should be the same
We need to have a medicine delivery robot
It should be deployed in a hospital
Show it a map
Then start delivering medicines
No need to fine-tune those data anymore
No need
It's just a large model
So no fine-tuning is needed at all
It may have medical specialization
Then let me ask you a very simple question
Think about why
I just mentioned dual arms
How important dual-arm robots are
If the medicine comes in a bottle
You need to twist it open
Requires both hands
So this is the foundation
Foundation
When you hire someone
They say "I'm a nurse"
But is it possible that I can't open the medicine bottle?
So this feeling is like
I think if we develop further for another ten years
we'll reach Westworld
Westworld
That movie
TV series
Wow, this feels so close
Yeah, I feel it's really close
At least if we live well
We might see it in our lifetime
Hope you never have to go to the hospital
May you never need hospitalization
Then we won't have to
So theoretically we're in
Because I also saw in
this DeepMind's Demis
he also researches these proteins
these medical breakthroughs
I think over there
there should be similar breakthrough developments
Yeah, we're using
this machine learning approach
Take for example AlphaFold
projects like this
many people in Taiwan now
have already started applying them
There used to be a lot of
biotech investments in Taiwan
Now there are many people
saying it's over fifteen thousand
The user is using AlphaGo in Taiwan
OK
Because it seems
Because I recently saw an FDA report
That is, the US FDA
They are actually already
feeling that this is being accelerated
when it comes to AI-related hardware
and healthcare-related areas are accelerating
They are trying to figure out a way
whether there's a method to speed up
the approval process for these things
and get them tested quickly
Then there's a chance to launch earlier
Or go straight through
Be adopted by everyone on a large scale sooner
Yeah, benefit humanity
For medical topics, there shouldn't be too many
unlicensed practitioners
Okay
Let me ask a broader question then
What is your definition of AGI?
Suddenly came here
This topic change came quite abruptly
But I think
Because we just
I think because it's already reached full modality
And because some people feel that
This is already indistinguishable from how humans do things
It's almost impossible to tell the difference
Can't tell the difference anymore
Some people are arguing that
Because according to the previous question's theory it should be
When do you think AGI will arrive
Then the next question would be
So how do you define AGI? What do you think AGI is?
So I quickly asked first: What is AGI?
Let me start by saying that
I think many people have a misunderstanding about AGI
The reason for this misunderstanding
is that when some people talk about AGI
they mean it's exactly like humans
has the same intelligence
but some people
when he talks about AGI
he actually means
superhuman intelligence
intelligence that surpasses human capabilities
those who talk about the singularity
mean that
When its intelligence reaches a certain level
the point where it continues to surpass humans
is called singularity
Singularity
So why approach it this way?
Why talk about it from this perspective?
I would say that
From my personal viewpoint
Individual
Personally, I think about AGI
I believe there are two things
that are extremely important
It has just been explained in great detail
about one particular aspect, which is that
this AI cannot exist solely within its own
a virtual world
but needs to be integrated into the human world
So this is what I consider to be
an interface between humans and artificial intelligence
a starting point
a startup point
So this is something I feel that
In 2024-2025, we're beginning to feel
this is starting to happen
This is one part of AGI
Another aspect I think
more important than this
because the former is
an integration with the physical world
an interface
an understanding
an interaction of situated understanding
The second part is actually
Have you noticed one thing
Interactions between people
A common contradiction we often observe
is what?
I've already told you
How to do this
Why don't you know how yet
I don't understand
Have you ever argued with your wife or girlfriend
That's how the argument started
The interaction between humans and machines
will have the same problem
meaning if I've already taught you once
Why don't you know it yet
So the next AGI
The most important starting point
I personally believe that
You need to be able to do it
I'll teach you once
and you'll know how to do it from then on
This is so hard
The reason is that now I
because I'm someone who can't code at all
I have no connection with computer science
and now I'm starting to use
vibe coding did some things
When I explained to it what needed to be done
it still didn't
maybe my communication skills are too poor
I always blame myself for my poor communication skills now
First, I reflect on myself
Then it's because my expression was inadequate
So it didn't do the right thing
What you're saying is quite interesting
What is it?
Because why do people feel that
Perhaps it's my poor communication skills
Why don't people interact with each other in this way
Why doesn't he say it like that
Right?
When you argue with your girlfriend
Didn't I already teach you once?
Why don't you ever question whether
Maybe it's because you didn't explain it well
So this is about the interaction between people
and the current interaction between humans and machines
imbalance point
because we feel that
Interacting with machines
The machine must be dumber than me
So I need to teach it many times
That's perfectly normal
But when AGI arrives
It should be as intelligent as I am
You should learn it after I teach you once
It feels very similar to what we just discussed
Exactly
Can we expect something different over time
The day your grandma
scolds the robot at home saying
I already taught you once, why don't you get it yet?
that's when you'll know AGI has arrived
OK, another criterion we use to judge
whether AGI has been achieved
is your grandmother
Indeed
And we found NVIDIA's standard quite interesting that day
He said how do I judge this
The physical world Turing test has been breached
Meaning we can't tell whether
the house was just cleaned by a robot
The robot has already helped you with everything
folded the clothes and cleaned up
And their line of reasoning goes like this
Their Turing test is this
You say this is good, why?
Because, for example, you can
imagine in the future grandma saying
My socks should be placed in this drawer
Then the robot made another mistake
She said "I've already told you once"
Why does this keep happening?
Or talking about the robotic vacuum cleaner at home
I still often run into things
then get tangled up and stop
even though I've taught you many times
and set it up repeatedly
You still have to deal with tangled wires and such
It just feels like this thing is actually still quite dumb
We call it a smart robotic vacuum cleaner
But is it really smart?
When it has multimodal large models to accomplish this task
it won't get tangled up anymore
Indeed
It won't be stupid anymore
It can recognize what shouldn't be blended
Our standards are really high now
Because about 10 years ago we would have used iRobot
It works by collision
meaning it bumps into walls
and at that moment I thought
Okay, not bad, it's better than how I used to sweep
Then later I thought bumping into things was really stupid
But now we have this infrared technology
And with visual sensing, I already feel
Wow, this is so much better than iRobot
Now I think it's stupid for getting tangled in wires
Then you come back to blame it
Have you noticed how your expectations keep changing?
So the next step would be
I already told you not to mess with that place where there are wires
Why did you still go and mess with it?
Just wait until your grandma starts scolding that robot vacuum
Then you'll know AGI has arrived
The robotic vacuum cleaner is truly
Our world's AGI is judged by this
Our measuring standard grows from Grandma
Grows from this kind of grandma
It's her expectation
If I've already told you once
Don't make this mistake again
And in fact, things like this are
extremely important in many application scenarios
Indeed
Take medical robots we just discussed for example
If he delivers the wrong medicine, that would be very serious.
I think it might take some time for everyone to get used to it.
Then some people who start getting accustomed to it will help deliver your medicine.
And believe they're more accurate than humans
It's like driving
Like autonomous vehicles
You can think of it this way
If we can achieve delivery robots
Why can't we have a medicine delivery robot
Medicine delivery can be fatal
So you're thinking in the right direction
Meaning this technology isn't nonexistent
But the question is, what are its regulations?
What is its reliability?
What is its robustness?
I think it's also related to autonomous driving
is similar
from a decade ago when people were talking about assisted driving
to fully autonomous driving
whether you look at Waymo or other autonomous driving systems
I think right now it's
when you see it, you find it incredible
it seems very popular abroad
but hasn't been seen in Taiwan yet
You can really feel there's still a difference
But foreign regulations have indeed been making continuous efforts to adjust
Allowing operations in places like Texas or California
And many people have already started in our area
In that area of California
people have already started saying
I'd rather have my child ride in Waymo's
self-driving car
Because I know that's safe
Oh, right
Isn't this exactly the transformation we were just talking about?
Yes
So we need to think about
It's not about what the trend of technological development is
but rather where its turning point lies
Yes, because just a few years ago people were still very concerned
about whether this autonomous driving assistance would work
But I feel this voice is changing
Especially, I think Taiwan might not be there yet
But because I've already been using this
self-driving technology
Maybe four years
But the past four years have been
So I feel this matter is no longer that
Surprising, is it?
Strange, right?
Right, and haven't there been many
issues related to driving in Taiwan recently?
So I think we should move forward
People gradually develop an acceptance of this technology
They start to think
Hey, isn't autonomous driving even safer?
It's like when medicine delivery robots perform exceptionally well
He would expect the medication delivery robot to have a lower error rate than
an actual nurse
or even that it wouldn't yell at you
Hey, why haven't you taken your medicine yet?
Just keeps offering you food
Can repeat endlessly
Never gets annoyed
A nurse might get annoyed by the third time
The temper flares up, but robots don't
It's something we should be able to see within our lifetime
Finally, what are your thoughts on this
For example, in Taiwan now
young people in their early 20s
if they want to start a business now
this is a
What advice would you give to those considering entering similar industries?
What kind of suggestions do you think should be offered?
In the field of AI?
Yes, in the field of AI
I think the most important issue right now is
the technology is changing extremely fast
so the most important
piece of advice is actually to be adaptive
And you shouldn't be thinking about just the present
but rather consider three months, six months, or a year from now
I've shared some thoughts today
new ideas
It allows you to
What I want to do
I think the interesting part about today's conversation is
Many people ask me questions when
Are you asking what I predict?
What I want to do isn't to tell you my predictions
but rather to teach you that skill
so you can make predictions yourself
Yes
This is where creativity truly begins
So I think the most important point is
From the perspective of adaptive ability
I think if we say
Taiwan's software industry as well
friends in the hardware industry
what they need to do is be adaptive
and be able to see these messages
Then began doing work that could make predictions
It's actually a kind of curiosity
Followed by continuous cultivation of exploration
And then quickly adapts through adoption
Then I noticed that many speeches abroad
actually show these industry leaders reaching similar conclusions
because technological advancements are accelerating too rapidly
this model has evolved from language models to multimodal
It's only been about two or three years
And this pace shows no signs of slowing down
Because just a few years ago we were still worried about whether the data might disappear
And then everything would stop
But this wall doesn't seem to exist
Haven't encountered this bottleneck
But even if it stops
All current multimodal things
There are already plenty of things that can be done
Yes, that's correct
This issue with the data
I think many people are stuck at a
I put this thing into a pre-trained model
Then this pre-trained model acquires this knowledge
After acquiring this knowledge
It can then perform many, many other tasks
It's stuck in that mindset
But now with the development of large models
It's actually not a completely pre-trained model
That's not the thinking pattern
but rather that these large models
have already begun to explore on their own
This is the biggest difference
So as I was just saying
The part I'm talking about
For example, if I teach you once
It should be able to
Learn it afterwards, right?
In fact, it won't just teach you once
It will learn
It will continue to explore
And extrapolate from one example
Understood
So that marks the true beginning of AGI
It needs to be able to integrate into this real world
First
second one
I'll teach you once
Don't make me teach you repeatedly
That's called machine learning
That's not called AI
And thirdly,
It's a matter of drawing inferences from one instance
started learning on my own
So currently the hottest research direction is..
In fact, it's the machine's self-learning
self-improvement
So everyone
Because inevitably people will feel anxious
It means some people constantly consume AI-related information
Like during that Google I/O week
You know
You feel very anxious
Information overload
I don't feel anxious
But there were a few days
When I went vibe coding by myself again
Then I didn't open Twitter for a few days
So I didn't see anything
One day I opened Twitter
Wow, explosion
Why so many new things
But I think there's one advantage
you don't have to worry
about missing anything
because if you check again tomorrow or five days later
there will be a bunch of new things
There's always something new
But if you choose a direction
And keep exploring
I think it's truly the best time
I think many people don't understand where anxiety comes from
Anxiety stems from
your fear of the future
So it's a fear of the future
So why do I have some today
segments that are particularly focused on
how to talk to everyone about predicting the future
The reason is that if you can predict the future
you will be relatively more calm
you will have less anxiety
the more you understand its potential direction
the more reassured you'll feel
Right, so if you're just absorbing that information
Then you get this feeling of overload
But you're not making any further predictions
You still feel like the future is uncontrollable
out of control
or something unpredictable
your anxiety will naturally rise
so that's what everyone is feeling right now
very anxious and highly stressed
The reason is that it stems from last time at this place
Many people in the company often tell me
Why do I feel you're very calm
I say the reason is because
I don't know for sure I'm right
but I think I know where the future is
then you won't feel so anxious
you already know what's gonna happen
To some extent, my own feeling about this matter is
because we've seen so many sci-fi movies
science fiction novels
I think Americans
Americans also grew up watching these things
And their feeling about this technology is
This was already something we saw in our novels
We just made it happen
Then I said, oh yeah
Because that's the best-case scenario
It's just like Star Trek
We have reached this utopian form of cosmic civilization
And then there's the other extreme that's really bad
Like Terminator
Skynet - that's the worst one
But I think every situation has its own
So it's great that we're living in the future
I think as producers
Those who make films definitely
Use their imagination to think of extremes
Because only extreme things have
Conflict and drama
That's what creates drama and box office appeal
That's a perfectly normal thing
But from the perspective of us ordinary people looking at these things
I think we'd feel that
It's just giving you a framework to think about the future
You need to look at the current direction of technology
to determine
I think this possibility is higher
than the other possibility
If you make this prediction
you'll feel a bit more at ease
Indeed
Alright, let's discuss some final topics
meaning outside of your work responsibilities
What kind of exercise do you do?
The exercise I do most often is golf
I'm absolutely obsessed with golf right now
I think about it all day long
Are all the golf courses in Taiwan available?
I haven't had the chance to play at golf courses in Taiwan yet
Because every time I come back, I start
Asking around which friends enjoy playing golf
Let's go play together
So to our audience friends
If you know of any good courts
The doctor is very interested
There might be some AI-integrated stuff
AI ball boy
I heard that in places like Korea
They already have those self-driving golf carts
That makes sense
Because it's a limited domain
I don't even know if Taiwan has adopted these technologies
I don't know either
I'm not familiar with golf
How about you recently
Do you have any recommendations, whether it's books or
TV series
or any other works you've been watching recently
Right after I got off the plane
I watched a segment of the Dune movie
Have you seen it?
That Chinese name
Doom
No
No, it's a sci-fi set in a desert
Dune
Yes, Dune Part 1 and Part 2
After watching it, I felt that
The entire visual presentation
is absolutely stunning
It looks amazing even on those terrible airplane screens
I think you could
You can probably feel that
because we were just talking about anxiety
I really enjoy certain sports
or some everyday activities
something that helps me relax
and completely takes my mind off
current matters
You see, playing golf also requires intense focus
You simply wouldn't think about work-related matters at all
ok I thought
Relax
Because everyone just
You might have a companion to chat with
And then
Play some ball while having a beer
It's really comfortable
Indeed
The pressure at work is already overwhelming enough
There's no need
Dune is truly a beautiful film
Especially when you're
I actually watched it on a plane
And it was in economy class
I looked at the screen and thought
My god, this screen is so terrible
The visuals are already so stunning
I can only imagine how much more impressive it would be
on a bigger screen
or in a better viewing environment
Yes
Did the AI recommend any books?
What do you think I should read?
Works related to AI
I'm quite interested
Looking forward to
I only recently learned about Taiwan
Over the past dozen months or so
Actually talking about that Zhang Zhimou
Biography of Morris Chang
I'm quite interested in
buying a few copies to read
you
I heard there's a part one and part two, right?
Part one was released a long time ago
And part two was just recently released
But it seems there isn't an English version yet
It seems it's still only available in Chinese version
Chinese version is fine
I can read Chinese just fine
Oh, I see, OK
Okay
Then finally, let me ask you to share
how you've been using AI recently
any tips
or one thing you frequently use
What can you use it for?
I've been doing it a lot recently
Let me give you a very interesting recent example
You can't use this
I recently used it once
A particularly interesting scenario
was
I recently went to Sydney for a meeting
Then we just talked about
I like playing golf
And Sydney
happens to be a harbor city
Yes
So I knew that in Sydney
and there have been some really amazing players who came from there
so I thought to myself, I'm going to Sydney
no matter what, I have to go play a game there
But before I go, I need to do some research
Because there are many different types of golf courses
Some are by the seaside
Some are not by the seaside
There are some places where you can play ball with kangaroos
And then there are some courts that are private
You can't enter
Only club members are allowed to enter
Some are open
Then different prices at different times
And there's also the issue of availability
I'll just ask Gemini directly
Do deep research for me
I said I would be in Sydney's downtown
I have a few free days
I want to play a game of basketball
Then I hope to be able to play ball by the seaside
Can you tell me
How long is the driving time
Do they have rental clubs
And how much does it cost?
And which day is available?
Do it completely for me
So everything went smoothly for you too
A report comes out, ten to twenty pages long
How about this stadium
What do you think of this stadium
What's the evaluation like
Can do it all
Just like a personal assistant
Actually played that game
And was very happy
Having a great time playing
OK this was an awesome experience
Because sometimes in the past
For example two years ago I might have used this feature
I still think it might have
That's OpenAI
OpenAI is still hallucinating
It's just giving you a bunch of fake stuff
It uses brute force
Yeah
But now with Gemini's deep research
It has added these internet-connected data capabilities
So the accuracy has greatly improved
I've also used Gemini's deep research
To do things like paper analysis
It performs exceptionally well
So now I feel many of these tasks
that used to be very tedious
are now being handled by online bots for you
Well, thank you Dr. Ji Huaixin for sharing so much with us today
Thank you for coming
Thank you
Goodbye